

Marco Richetta

- ♀ Copenhagen, Denmark | ☑ marcorichetta@gmail.com
- marcorichetta.vercel.app | In marco-richetta | 🕥 marcorichetta

About Me

I'm a software engineer with +5 years of experience, mostly focused on **backend** with Python. Also have experience in **DevOps** and frontend with **React**.

I like to share knowledge by giving <u>talks</u>, being a <u>mentor</u> or simply helping others to solve problems. <u>E.g. the Django forum</u>.

Currently interested in working on **Developer Experience (DX)**, specially through IaC. Also learning about Go, MLOps, Elixir.

Experience

Software Engineer, Mercado Libre - Córdoba, Argentina

Jul 2022 - Jun 2024

- Worked improving **Python DX**, maintaining tooling used by thousands of developers in the company. (General support, features, bugfixes, version deprecation).
- Building on our Python expertise, we led upgrades for over 1,000 outdated Java applications and libraries using <u>Large-Scale Code Changes</u>, managing the roadmap and collaborating with responsible teams to implement and monitor each update.

Software Developer, Flux IT – Córdoba, Argentina

Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

- Fullstack development (**React/Django**) to integrate 3rd party systems with internal company applications.
- Later, in a more **DevOps** role, I helped in the migration of the internal infrastructure to Kubernetes applying **GitOps**. This also led to better DX.

Education

BS Computer Systems Analyst, Instituto Superior 25 de Mayo – Feb 2015 - Dec 2020 Córdoba, Argentina

Volunteering

Hack Your Future: Joined as a Technical mentor to help people kickstart their programming carreers. - https://www.hackyourfuture.dk/

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript/Typescript, Go

Technologies: Django, Pytest, React, Kubernetes, FluxCD, Docker, OpenTelemetry

Languages: Spanish (native), English (professional proficiency), Danish (learning)